http://www.odu.edu/oduhome/privacy.shtml

[ skip to content ]
Phone menu jump toggle
Internet Privacy Statement
We reserve the right to amend our Internet Privacy Policy and Internet Privacy Policy Statement at any time without notice.
Governing laws
ODU protects records in accordance with our obligations as defined by applicable Virginia statutes, including, but not limited to, the Virginia Privacy Protection Act of 1976, the Virginia Freedom of Information Act, and by any applicable U.S. federal laws.
Links to other websites
The website may contain links to other public or private websites, whose privacy practices we do not control. ODU does not take responsibility for the privacy practices of those websites or their content practices. You should check each website in order to understand its privacy policy
Information we collect
Routing information
The Internet domain and Internet address of the computer you are using.
Essential technical information
Identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system and the time and date of access.
Nonessential technical information
The Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our website.
Optional information
When you send email, we collect your name, email address and the content of your email. When you complete online forms, we collect the data you choose to submit and confirm.
How information is collected and used
In general, users may visit the Old Dominion University website without being asked to share personal information. There are times, however, when personal information must be collected. There is no legal requirement for you to provide any information at our website. You should also be aware that it may be not be possible to complete business transactions using this Web site without this personal information. As an example, ODU may require your e-mail address in order to communicate with you. In providing information to ODU through this Web site, you are agreeing to make such information available to the University so that it can meet its educational and business objectives.
The following clarifies how the University may use personal information
Fulfilling a request
When requesting information or services from the University, the information you provide will be used in order to satisfy that request. Information may be shared with a third-party to provide indirect support in fulfilling your request.
Account & log on information
When you use certain university websites, log on and account information may be collected and used by the website to authenticate your identity so that you may receive a variety of information resources and services. The website does not maintain copies of this account and log on information; it is ephemeral, meaning that is only used to validate your identity so that you can obtain the information or services you requested.
Usage information
ODU routinely analyzes usage patterns on the website in order to better provide services to Internet users, primarily students, faculty and staff of the University. As an example, we routinely collect Web pages access information, domain names where web pages are accessed, time of day, and the version of the browser used. This information is used to provide a better Web browsing experience for people who use of Web servers the University maintains.
Use of "cookies"
This Web server makes use of "cookies." A cookie is a small piece of information (or data) that the Web server may send in your Internet browser, which is usually stored on your computer. Cookies are designed to improve your Web browsing experience and to make the website more useful. However, you may choose to disable cookies from your Internet browser. This may affect website functionality for you.
Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA)
Refer to the DMCA Notices Page for more information.
Pop up advertisement disclaimer
The Pop-Up advertisements you may be seeing on Old Dominion University's Home page are not coming from the Old Dominion University website. The advertisements are not generated by Old Dominion University and the University has not contracted with anyone for such advertisement services. Some Internet sites are programmed to create Pop-up windows when you exit them. When you visit the Old Dominion University website after surfing these websites, you may experience Pop-up windows on the screen. Also, some free ware programs that you may have installed on your system may cause these Pop-up windows. . These programs (for example: Music and File sharing) support themselves by agreeing to install advertising packages with their product. For more information see this article by wired.com If you are experiencing this problem, you can help us track it by sending email to webadmin@odu.edu
Information Technology Services
4300 Engineering & Computational Sciences Building
Norfolk,
VA
23529
757-683-3189 (office)
757-683-5155 (fax)
itshelp@odu.edu
Old Dominion University, located in the coastal city of Norfolk, is Virginia's entrepreneurial-minded doctoral research university with more than 24,000 students, rigorous academics, an energetic residential community, and initiatives that contribute $2.6 billion annually to Virginia's economy.
Connect with #ODU
Copyright © Old Dominion University •
Updated 4/23/2013
Privacy
•
Accessibility
•
Consumer Information
